Bo Salinas

San Antonio, Tx

Phone: 512-630-7076 | Email: bo.salinas12@gmail.com LinkedIn: bosalinas@linkedin.com | GitHub: bosalinas@github.com |

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Education and a lifelong dedication to learning. Experienced in leading teams in deploying functional applications and websites. Experienced in planning curriculum and leading a team to learn best-practice teaching strategies. Effective at combining creativity and problem-solving to develop user-friendly applications.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL, GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, Express, React, Node, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp Certificate

University of Texas San Antonio, San Antonio, Tx

An intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

BA in Psychology: Texas State University, San Marcos, Tx

PROJECTS

Code Wizard

Github | Live

Summary: Application for taking guizzes online

- Role: Full-stack developer
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, React, Procreate

Get Sh*t Done

Github | Live

Summary: Application for creating to-do lists

- Role: Front-end developer
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, React,

Yass Flix

Github | Live

Summary: Website for searching movies by title

- Role: Back-end developer
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Foundations, Javascript, Watchmode API, TMDB API

Password Generator

Github I Live

Summary: Simple website to provide secure passwords

- Role: Front-end logic
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript

EXPERIENCE

Learning Tech Specialist University of Texas San Antonio

2022 - 2023

San Antonio, Tx

Worked in Academic Innovation, focusing on faculty and student learning inside Blackboard and Canvas. Provided one-on-one instruction to faculty and students to understand the LMS. Assisted in teaching and fixing errors with integrated tools and features.

Key Accomplishments:

- Reduced average resolution time, improving overall customer experience
- Started a more user-friendly knowledge base that is both internal and user-facing

RTI Coordinator

2021 - 2022

Brooks Collegiate Academy

San Antonio, Tx

Assisted teachers in creating lesson plans, modifying and differentiating lessons to fit all learners. Collected data and collaborated with grade level teams to address students with academic and behavioral struggles. Delegated tasks to paraprofessionals and created an open communication environment.

Key Accomplishments:

- Set the standard for new styles of teaching and data-tracking as the first in this role
- Developed professional development for educators and staff on new procedures and best teaching practices

Special Education Teacher Northside ISD

2019 - 2021

San Antonio, Tx

Taught in an inclusion setting within three different grade levels. Tracked goal progress and created specialized lesson plans reflecting individual needs of students. Collaborated regularly with PT, OT, and SLPs to ensure positive progress for all students.

Key Accomplishments:

- Improved academic performance and achievement levels of special education students through targeted instructional strategies and interventions.
- Prioritized collaborative communication and scheduling between 3-4 teams at a time

Special Education Assistant

2019

Northside ISD

San Antonio, Tx

Responsible for the education and behavioral management of a student with autism. Tutored, tracked behavioral progress, scribed, and overall management of the student.

Key Accomplishments:

 Effectively managed crisis situations and implemented crisis intervention strategies to ensure the safety and well-being of students

Sales Associate 2016-2019

Home Depot Georgetown,Tx

Worked to provide outstanding customer service, on occasion operated cash registers, assisted customers with finding the correct product, and independently opened and closed the department.

Key Accomplishments:

Received awards for being a top-performing sales associate for the department